Remember...
牢記
You have early stage Alzheimer's.
你有早期的老年癡呆癥
- Have you gone to a vacation or something? - No.
-你去渡假了嗎 -冇有
- So Munir has never been alone? - No.
-Munir從來冇有一個人嗎？-不
You forgot to give water to your cat.
你忘給貓喝水了
How does it feel to be the only woman working in an homicide bureau？
作為兇殺局唯一的女性員工感覺如何？
I chose you from 50 girls.
我從五十個女孩中選了你
How nice.
真好啊
Since I won't remember, I can do anything I want, is that so?
因為我不記得了，所以我可以做任何我想做的事情，是嗎？
Exactly.
正是
Do you have farsighted glasses?
你有遠視眼鏡嗎？
I MET A GIRL TODAY. HER NAME WAS NEVRA ELMAS.
我今天遇到了一個名字叫NEVRA ELMAS的女孩
Chief Inspector Tolga Yazgan: Who is this?
首席檢查官Tolga Yazgan：這是誰？
I must have dialed the wrong number.
打錯了吧
This is Mehmet Yurtgil's home, miss. Who were you calling?
這是Mehmet Yurtgil的家，小姐您找誰？
I am his daughter. I was calling my dad.
我是他的女兒，我打電話給我父親
Did something happen to him? Hello?
他出什麼事了嗎？
Yes... I'm afraid so, miss.
是的，小姐
DO NOT CROSS POLICE LINE
不要越過警察線
Follow me.
跟我走
- Who did this, then? - I don't know.
-是誰幹的？-我不知道
You?
您？
If you're hiding something, you'll be complicit. You know that?
如果你隱瞞了什麼事情，你會變成同謀。知道嗎？
I told you. I don't know him.
我告訴過你，我不認識他
Neither his wife, nor him.
也不認識他妻子
So be it.
就這樣吧
Whoever killed him, must know you, then.
不管誰殺了他，兇手一定認識你，然後……
Think about it.
思考一下
Who is able to commit such a thing around you?
你身邊誰能做出這種事情？
- Nobody. - How do you know?
-冇人 -你怎麼知道？
I know everybody.
我了解身邊的人
None of them could do such a bad thing.
他們誰都做不出這種事情
This is murder.
這是謀殺
Me?
我？
For instance.
例如
You think I could do it?
你認為我能做到嗎？
No.
冇有
You know why you say no?
你知道為什麼說不嗎？
Because you're afraid to say yes.
因為你害怕說是
Why would I be afraid?
我為什麼會害怕呢？
Because if you said yes, then I could...
因為如果你說是，那我可以……
Here, in the middle of this road,
在這條路上
just shoot and kill you.
把你殺掉
And nobody would really know.
冇有人知道
You'd be terrified. Understand?
你會害怕的，明白嗎？
All the evil in this world is done by people we don't really know.
這個世界上所有的邪惡都是我們不認識的人造成的
That's why the first thing we do when we wake up is...
這就是為什麼我們醒來時要做的第一件事是……
To fool ourselves.
自欺欺人
So I'm asking again.
所以我再問一次
Who could have done such a thing?
誰能做出這樣的事情？
I have no idea.
我不知道
Chief...
長官
Agah. Agah.
Agah! Agah! Please!
Agah! Agah! 快停下！
Agah!
Agah, what have you done?
Agah，你幹嘛？
庫爾德語
Here you go.
好了
What have you done?
你做了什麼？
Take that out of the rent.
從租金中扣吧
What time is it?
幾點了？
- Ten past one. - Good, there's time.
-1點10分 -好，還有時間
Sorry, Agah, how do you know Kurdish?
抱歉，Agah，您怎麼會說庫爾德語？
- Kurdish, why? - You just spoke it.
-庫爾德語，為什麼這麼問？-你剛才說了
Sometimes she doesn't recall her own name.
有時候她甚至不記得自己的名字
Can't you see her?
你看不出來嗎？
What could my mum tell you?
我媽媽能告訴你什麼？
She dances well, I heard.
她跳舞跳的很好
- Didn't they have a caretaker? - Of course they had.
-他們冇有保姆嗎？-當然有
But my dad, bless him.
但是我爸
He was a difficult person.
他是一個很難相處的人
Whoever they hired left after three days.
不管雇傭什麼人都堅持不了三天
The last one left a week ago.
一周前最後一個也走了
They were alone since.
自從那以後就隻有他們倆
Do you have the details of the caretakers?
您有保姆的詳細信息嗎？
Yes. I have everything.
是的，我都有
We spoke all the time.
我們一直都有聯係
I'll give the numbers.
我會把電話號碼給你
Can we leave now?
我們現在可以離開了嗎？
Sure. You've had quite a journey.
當然，您經曆了艱難的一天
One last thing.
最後一件事
Anybody who'd want to kill your father?
有人想殺你父親嗎？
Any name comes to mind?
能想到誰嗎？
Who'd want to kill him?
誰想殺了他？
Miss! Your father was a judge in criminal court.
小姐！你父親是刑事法院的法官
He must have put somebody in prison.
他一定把某人送進了監獄
But he retired years ago.
但是他幾年前退休了
- Since you're coming from Madrid... - Olé!
-自從您去馬德裏以來……  -Olé！
Mom!
媽媽！
Let me tell you this way:
這樣說吧：
- Bullfighters fight until they retire. - Olé!
-鬥牛士戰鬥到退休 -Olé！
Mom.
媽媽
- But bulls fight until they die. - Olé!
-但是公牛奮戰到死 -Olé！
- Olé! - Mom!
-Olé！-媽媽！
- Olé! - Mom.
-Olé！-媽媽
MY CAR TAKES PETROL. NOT DIESEL!
我的車是用汽油的，不是柴油
All right, sir.
好了先生
- You fill it up? - Yes, I made it "full".
-加滿嗎？-是的，我加“滿”了
- Petrol. - Yes.
-汽油-是
Good.
好
But I'll tell you something.
告訴你件事
You don't make something full.
你不能讓某件東西“滿”
It doesn't exist in any language.
它不存在於任何語言中
Don't use it again, okay?
不要再這樣說了，好嗎？
Better forget the word.
最好忘記這個詞
Wouldn't that be awesome?
那不是很棒嗎？
If we forget everything wrong,
如果我們忘記所有錯誤
and only remember the correct things?
隻記得正確的事情？
But don't you worry.
但是你不用擔心
There's a lot of wrong in here. For example...
這裏有很多錯誤，例如……
I thought my daughter was happy, but she wasn't.
我以為女兒很福祉，但實際上並不是
- Sir, it's 200. - Huh?
-先生200 -嗯？
200. Your bill.
200，您的賬單
Take that upstairs.
拿到樓上去
We've flown 20 hours, and the car ride tired me more.
我們已經飛了20個小時，坐車讓我更纍了
Why do you say that?
為什麼這麼說
You took the scenic route, like a cabbie.
您像開出租車一樣沿著風景優美的路線
The usual route had rush hour.
常規路線這個時候會堵車
That's...
這……
That's why.
這就是為什麼
You've been living here for years. How could you be confused?
您在這裏住了多年了，怎麼會感到睏惑？
I wasn't confused.
我並不感到睏惑
- You didn't eat anything. - I'm not hungry.
-你什麼都冇吃 -我不餓
Are you ill or something?
你生病了嗎？
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
Dad, what the hell?  I just left my bloody house.
爸，怎麼回事，我剛剛離開了我自己的家
What do you mean, ill?
你什麼意思，生病了？
Okay. Won't you go back?
好吧，不能回頭了嗎？
- Are you kicking us out? - Of course not...
-你要趕我們出去嗎 -當然不是
Don't worry. We won't stay long.
別擔心，我們不會待久
- I didn't say anything. - Isn't number eight empty anyway?
-我什麼也冇說 -八號房間不是空的嗎？
We'll stay there.
我們會留在那裏
I'll find myself a job.
我會找一份工作
I could pay rent, too. Okay?
我也可以付租金，好嗎？
Dad...
爸
I'm saying that I took my child,
我是說我帶著我的孩子，
I left my house and come here.
我離開家來到這裏
You're asking me if I'm... I'm not going back!
你還問我能不能回頭？
- Okay, don't. - I'm not!
-好的，不要 -不能了！
All right, don't go.
好啦，不要走
Never mind.
冇關係
I can't take it anymore.
我受不了了
- I just can't. - I beg of you, Zuhal.
-我不能 -我求你了，Zuhal
Daddy!
爸爸！
Please, Zuhal. My baby.
拜托，Zuhal，我的寶貝
- What will I do now, daddy? - You'll make him sad, too.
-爸爸，我現在該怎麼辦？-你也會讓你兒子也傷心的
But I just rented number eight.
但是有人剛租了八號房
He just moved in.
他剛搬進去
CRIMINAL COURTS OF PEACE
刑事和解
THE NEW JUDGE VISITED THE DISTRICT GOVERNOR
新法官訪問地區總督
Speak with the lab yet?
跟實驗室溝通了嗎？
I did. They're working on it.
嗯，他們正在處理
I was just trying to see where he previously worked.
我想看看他以前在哪裏工作
Maybe I could see something.
也許我能發現一些東西
They'll call after the autopsy.Don't go anywhere.
屍檢後他們會打電話，不要離開
- Won't you go in? - Who am I?
-你不去嗎？ -我是誰啊？
We have you, after all.
畢竟有你在呢
But leave the file on my desk so I'll teach you to read.
把文件放在我的桌子上，我會教你怎麼看
Teach her to write, too.
也要教她寫
Ever seen me half-ass something?
你見過我做事做一半的時候嗎？
Of course I will.
我當然會
It's my job.
這是我的工作
True.
是哦
See, I can write.
我會寫
Don't have to teach me that.
不用教我
I MET AN OAF TODAY. HIS NAME WAS FIRUZ.
我今天遇到一個笨蛋，他的名字叫FIRUZ
- Did he go to sleep? - Yeah.
-他睡覺了嗎-是的
Is the bed all right?
床可以嗎？
It is, it is but...
可以，但是
I wish it could be all right up here.
我希望這裏一切都好
- Is that my Walkman? - Uh-huh.
-那是我的隨身聽嗎？-恩
- Does it still work? - It does.
-還能用嗎？-可以
Where's the TV, dad?
爸爸，電視在哪？
I gave it to someone who needed it.
我給了需要它的人
- Don't you watch it? - I watched forty years of it.
-你不看嗎？-我看了四十年了
- Okay, good night then. - Good night, sweetie.
-好的，晚安 -晚安，親愛的
- Zuhal. - What?
-Zuhal -什麼？
Take the spare key in that bowl.
拿那個碗裏的備用鎖匙
I gave one to Deva, too.
也給Deva一個
Yes?
餵？
Okay.
好的
I'll be there in twenty minutes.
我二十分鍾就到
Good luck with that.
祝你好運
DEAR DIARY
日記
I ONLY TRUST HER. BECAUSE NEVRA UNDERSTANDS ME.
我隻相信她，因為Nevra了解我
Timur, are you in? It's me, Nevra.
Timur，你在嗎？我是Nevra
I'm coming...
我來了
Welcome.
歡迎
We've spoken before, but never met in person.
我們之前在電話是溝通過，但從未冇見過麵
Yes, hi.
是的，嗨
Nobody has any respect to the people in here. They barge in.
冇有人尊重這裏的人，他們會直接闖進來
That's why I lock the door.
這就是我鎖門的原因
I had something else to do. That's why I was late.
我還有其他事情要做，所以遲到了
You're just in time.
你來的剛剛好
I was on a break.
我剛才在休息
You'll get used to it.
你會習慣的
People get used to the dead.
人們習慣了死人
They can't harm anybody.
他們不能傷害任何人
Not anymore, I mean.
我是說不會再傷害了
The thing is to get used to the living.
要學著適應
That's the hard part.
那才是睏難的部分
You want something to drink? I can make some coffee.
你要喝點什麼嗎我可以煮咖啡
If you're making some for yourself.
如果你也要喝的話……
Did he really have a label on his forehead with your name on it?
他的額頭上曾貼有一個標有您名字的標簽嗎？
- Yeah. - A serial killer situation.
-是的-是連環殺手的風格
It is.
是的
But, difficult to find one in this country of course.
但是，在這個國家當然很難找到
There are no serial killers in Turkey.
土耳其冇有連環殺手
There are people who go on a killing spree.
他們瘋狂的殺人
Now...
好了……
The shot was in point-blank range.
這是近距離射擊
Less than two or three meters.
兩三米之內
No signs of a struggle.
冇有掙紮的跡象
He's been dead for 96 hours at the most.
死亡時間不超過96個小時
There's one entry wound, 7.65.
傷口隻有一處，7.65mm子彈
Any sugar or milk in your coffee?
咖啡加牛奶還是加糖？
Nope.
不用了
Hello?
餵？
Okay.
好的
I'll be there soon.
我很快就到
It was the lab. They found a match for the prints.
是實驗室打來的，他們匹配到了指紋信息
Seriously? You found him then?
真的嗎？你能找到他了嗎？
Thanks for the coffee.
謝謝你的咖啡
See you later.
回頭見
Your honor.
法官大人
When will you legalize this?
您什麼時候可以將其合法化？
Can you reach the prosecutor in charge?
您可以聯係到主管檢察官嗎？
We'll need a warrant of arrest.
我們需要逮捕令
I believe I'm getting the hang of this.
我確信我已經抓到兇手了
I really do.
真的
I wish Mebrure could see this.
我希望Mebrure能看到
We loved each other so.
我們彼此十分相愛
So many memories.
許多美好的回憶
My only hope
我唯一的希望
is to die before I forget them all.
是在我忘掉所有人之前就死了
But how would you know that? Right?
但是你怎麼知道呢？
Don't tell me that you loved too.
不要告訴我你也愛過
Yours isn't love. It's rancor.
你的不是愛而是仇恨
You don't love with rancor.
你不會帶著怨恨去愛
- Is that the man's home? - Yeah.
-這是兇手的家嗎？-是的
- He's armed, of course. - Probably, yes.
-他有武器 -應該是的
We'll go in, pick him up, then leave.
我們進去抓到他，然後離開
Pity.
可憐
You wasted it all.
你都浪費了
Your wife obviously loved you so much.
你老婆很愛你
Moved heaven and earth to make a home for you.
竭盡全力為你打造一個家
You took her for granted.
你卻把她當成理所當然
I forgive everything...
我可以原諒任何事
But I don't forgive anyone who takes his wife for granted.
但我不會原諒任何將妻子視為理所當然的人
I have to be frank. I'm sorry.
我必須坦率地說對不起
Don't look at me like that.
別這樣看著我
I could have picked somebody else.
我本來可以選別人的
But you're very guilty.
但是你罪孽深重
And you weren't properly punished.
而且你也冇有受到相應的懲罰
What's eight years?
什麼八年？
"Unjust provocation...
“因錶現良好……
Time off for good behavior." Mitigation after mitigation.
獲得減刑” 減刑後又減刑
They could have given you a medal too.
他們應該給你一枚獎章
I've read the trial records.
我已經看過了庭審記錄
They gave proper consideration
他們給予了適當的考慮
but they didn't deal proper retribution.
但他們冇有進行適當的懲罰
Therefore...
因此
You're getting your real punishment in here.
你將在這裏受到真正的懲罰
You know what your punishment is?
你知道你的懲罰是什麼嗎？
You'll be my murder weapon.
你將成為我殺人的武器
Good, isn't it?
很好，不是嗎？
Clear. Perp is not in. We're moving out.
安全，罪犯不在這裏，收隊
We're going in. We'll conduct a search.
我們進去搜查
That's Salih.
那是Salih
He's a decent lorry driver.
他是個不錯的卡車司機
He even helped us move,
他還幫我們搬過家
and Mebrure is extraordinarily fussy.
但Mebrure非常挑剔
You'll be killing Salih!
你將會把Salih殺掉
Come on.
來吧
Give me your finger.
手指伸出來
Don't be difficult, my back is aching up. Come on.
別難為人了，我的後背酸痛，快點
It was so easy the last time. Give me your finger.
上一次真的太容易了，手指伸出來
Look.
聽好了
If you'll be nice,
如果你錶現好
I'll handcuff you the other way. It'll be more comfortable. Deal?
我會用另一種方式給你戴手銬，那樣會舒服很多，好嗎？
Agreed? Come. Give me your finger.
同意嗎？來吧，手指給我
Come on, give it to me.
來吧給我
You're mad at me.
你在生我的氣
But anyone else would've cut it off.
但是如果換了別人會把你手指切掉的
We're done.
大功告成
Of course, only serving a sentence wouldn't do.
當然，隻服刑是不行的
You need rehabilitation.
你需要改過自新
What's a sentence good for without rehabilitation?
冇有悔過，服刑有什麼用呢？
Nothing.
冇用
Everyone collects something.
每個人喜歡都收集東西
And this is my collection.
這是我的收藏
I have a lot more, but this is special for you.
我還有很多，但這些對你有特殊意義
Keep this between us...
別告訴別人……
I pinched these from case files, back in the day.
這些是我從案卷裏偷來的
You look at them well,
你好好看看
and think of the nasty things that you've done.
想想你所做過的惡心事
Okay?
好嗎？
All things packed away, Along with yourself.
所有的東西都收拾好，伴隨著你自己
Memories are scattered, To the room, everywhere.
記憶零散，到房間，到處都是
The perfume I'm used to Is no longer there.
我習慣的香水不再存在
You.
你
Your smile has faded From the nooks of the house.
你的笑容從屋子的角落消失了
Loneliness is bitter.Please don't leave me.
孤獨很痛苦，請不要離開我
We have loved this Colorless world together.
我們一起愛過這個無色的世界
You.
你
My woman.
我的女人
Remember when In the street across.
記得在街對麵
We have kissed For the first time in my life.
我們有生以來第一次親吻
Locked in embrace One spring morning.
鎖定擁抱一個春天的早晨
You.
你
The lights are off The house is under dark.
燈滅了屋子裏一片漆黑
Our warm sunlit house Has now grown cold.
我們溫暖的陽光下的房子現在變得寒冷
Nights go on forever I keep on weeping.
夜永遠繼續我不斷哭泣
You.
您
My woman.
我的女人
- Oh dear! - Dad!
-天啊！-爸爸
So sorry, sweetie. I...
抱歉，親愛的，我……
You're up? Come in.
你起來了嗎
Of course I'm up. You knocked the door all night.
我當然起來了，你整晚都敲門
Zuhal! Deva speaks!
Zuhal！Deva說話了！
Deva spoke to me for the first time!
Deva第一次對我說話！
Good job, Deva! Good morning, Deva!
幹得好，Deva！早上好，Deva！
- Good morning. - Enjoy your breakfast, Deva.
-早上好-享受早餐，Deva
Come sweetie. Everything's ready.
來吧親愛的，一切都準備好了
I won't stay, daddy. I have to go out.
爸爸，我必須出去
There was this Onat in my old company.
我要去我以前的公司Onatin
I wrote to him yesterday about a job.
昨天我給他寫了一封求職信
- You just arrived, sweetie. - Yes.
-你才剛到這，親愛的-是的
But we have to settle down as soon as possible.
但是我們必須盡快安頓下來
I'll drop by Deva's school, too.
我還要去Deva的學校
I hope they don't give me a rough time, with it being mid-semester, and all.
我希望學校那邊不要因為是期中階段讓我難堪
Sit down, have some tea. I'll make you coffee.
坐下喝茶，我煮咖啡給你
I'll get something later.
等一下我去拿
You'll have a good time, grandfather and grandson.
祖父和孫子，你們會玩得很開心的
Sure. I'll show Deva around.
當然，我會帶他到處轉轉
May I have some bread, Deva?
我可以吃些麵包嗎，Deva？
You're free to be alone, if you want.
如果你願意的話，可以一個人呆著
Actually, you're free to be alone.
其實，你可以一個人呆著
I slept like a log last night.
我昨晚睡得很香
Nevra.
Sorry, Chief. I dozed off.
抱歉，長官，我睡著了
We ID'd the perp and raided his house last night...
昨晚我們確認了嫌犯並且搜查了他的房子
Okay, okay. Calm down.
好的，好的，放鬆
I've heard everything.
我都聽說了
Go home, get some sleep.
回家睡一下
Come back in the afternoon.
下午回來
But you had to inform Firuz last night.
但是你必須把昨晚的事告訴Firuz
- It all happened so quickly. - The damage is done.
-事情發生的太快了 -於事無補
You go home now, okay?
你現在回家吧，好嗎？
- Good night. - Good morning.
-晚安-早上好
Agah?
- Agah, how are you? - Thanks, Rustem. You?
-Agah，你好嗎？-謝謝，Rustem，你怎麼樣？
Fine, can't complain. Who's the lad?
很好，知足了，這小夥子是誰？
My grandson. He's arrived yesterday with his mother.
我的孫子，他昨天和他媽媽一起來的
Joyous news. You know your grandfather?
好消息啊，你認識你的祖父嗎？
He's a killer.
他是殺手
You've killed the instrument.
你已經把樂器弄死了
You stabbed the drum!
你刺了鼓！
But thanks. They were being obnoxiously loud.
但是謝謝你了，那鼓真的很煩人
We'll have some peace of mind.
這回我們安心了
See you later.
回頭見
Okay then.
好吧
- You stabbed a drum? - What?
-你刺壞了鼓嗎？-什麼？
Oh, it's not a big deal.
哦，冇什麼大不了的
Could I drop you off somewhere?
需要我把你送到什麼地方嗎？
Nah, I can go myself.
不，我可以自己走
Okay.
好的
Have fun, then.
祝你玩得開心
You too.
你也是
- Okay, see you later - Fine
-好的，待會見-很好
Salih the lorry driver.
卡車司機Salih
I know what you like.
我知道你喜歡什麼
I dropped in without an appointment, sorry.
我冇有預約就來了，對不起
Sending your CV would have been fine,
簡曆發過來就好
but Onat specially requested.
但Onat特殊要求
You lived in Australia?
你住在澳洲嗎？
Yes, four years in Sydney.
是的，在雪梨住了四年
We just came back.
我們剛回來
- Why the laugh? - I don't know.
-為什麼笑？-我不知道
People kill to be there, everyone's trying to leave.
大家都很想去那裏，每個人都想離開這
But you've come back.
但是你回來了
You were a former employee of ours?
你是我們以前的雇員嗎？
Yes, but...
對，但是
I mean... I worked here. But things changed a lot.
我的意思是我曾在這裏工作，但是情況發生了很大變化
You come to me every day like it's your job, and you leave a 100?
你每天都來找我，就像是你的工作一樣，才給100？
Go away.
滾蛋
This room hasn't changed.
這個房間冇變
Still the same.
還是一樣
Congratulations.
恭喜啦
No one drops by Human Resources,
人力資源部無人問津，
but you seem to remember it well.
你記得很清楚
No, this was my room.
不，這是我的房間
And the chair's the same, too.
椅子也一樣
That used to be my chair.
那曾經是我的椅子
This used to be another department?
這是其他部門的嗎？
No.
冇有
It was Human Resources.
是人力資源部
I was at your position.
我曾坐在你現在的位置
Really?
真的？
Miss...
小姐
Are you here to take my job away?
你是來接管我工作的嗎？
No.
不是
I thought that maybe you'd need some help.
我以為你可能需要一些幫助
How could you forget about filling up?
你怎麼可以忘記加油？
- Come in. - Doctor, I'm so sorry...
-進來 -醫生，我很抱歉……
- Doctor, it's important. - Sir, excuse me.
-醫生，這很重要 -先生，對不起
Agah, come in. Please, calm down.
Agah，請進來，冷靜一下
We're okay.
冇事的
I have to tell you.
我必須告訴你些事情
LADIES' ROOM
女廁所
Nevra.
If you pull anything like this again, I'll make you sorry. You hear me?
如果你再做這樣的事，我會讓你後悔的，你聽到了嗎？
If you have more of those threats, I'll stay in here.
如果你繼續威脅我的話，我就不出去了
Huh?
?？
Shit!
見鬼！
MESSAGE FROM THE KILLER
殺手留下的信息
What will I do?
我該怎麼辦？
If I'm already forgetting such vital things...
如果我能夠忘記了如此重要的事情
Should I change prescriptions, you think?
您認為我應該更改處方嗎？
I forget to fill up sometimes.
我有時也會忘記加油
Don't be so hard on yourself.
不要對自己要求這麼苛刻
No one can remember everything completely and without error.
冇有人能完全無誤地記住每件事
You'll run out of petrol or gas!
用完了汽油或者柴油，無所謂的
What's important is to stay calm.
重要的是要保持冷靜
And to find a solution.
並找到解決方案
You can't let anything out of the ordinary get to you.
你不能讓任何不尋常的事影響到你
Sometimes the best plan is to not have a plan.
有時最好的計畫就是冇有計劃
Make your mind up.
做個決定
Do I have a plan, or not?
我到底要不要做計劃？
Do. Do have your plan.
要做，繼續做好你的計劃
I'm telling you to make changes when necessary.
如果到了不用做計劃的時候我會告訴你
I get it. I'm not that old.
我知道，我還不那麼老
We're settled, then.
那就冇問題了
So I don't need to have a plan all the time.
所以我不需要一直都有計劃
No.
不用
Adapt yourself.
適應自己
If only we could plan everything in advance...
要是我們能提前計劃一切就好了……
There's luck to be reckoned with.
運氣也是不容忽視的
Sometimes you have to trust your luck,
有時候你必須相信自己的運氣，
and sometimes you just have to accept it.
有時你隻需要接受它
There's something else that's important.
還有一件很重要的事情
I used to work in the Silopi Court of Justice for three years.
我曾經在西羅皮法院工作了三年
I thought I forgot,
我以為我忘記了
but I didn't forget to speak Kurdish.
但我冇有忘記說庫爾德語
No ATMs... We've been looking all morning. Nothing!
冇有自動取款機，我們找了一個上午都冇找到
- We can't see the turn. - But everybody's seeing this.
-也冇看到轉彎 -但是大家都看到這個了
- How could this happen? - I've heard about it. I saw it.
-怎麼會這樣？-我聽說了
- But that's how he works. - Who is he?
-但這就是他的工作方式 -他是誰？
That charlatan journalist, Ates Arbay.
那個卑鄙的記者Ates Arbay
But I'm not mad at him.
但是我冇有生他的氣
I'm not mad at him!
我冇有生他的氣！
I'm mad at the idiot...
我對那個白癡生氣
I'm mad at the fool
我對那個傻瓜生氣
that sells this piece for a handful of money!
那個用這條消息換了幾百塊錢的傻B！
They'll send an inspector, and then we'll see!
將會有一名檢察官到這來，我們走著瞧！
That's what's going to happen.
那就是要發生的事
Don't we have any other footage?
我們冇有其他鏡頭嗎？
No, Chief.
冇了，長官
I don't want Deva to lose a year.
我不想讓Deva浪費這一年的時間
I see.
我懂
This relocation is already taking its toll on him.
這次搬家已經給他造成了很大影響
Of course.
當然
So what do you say?
您覺得怎麼樣呢？
You think something could be arranged? Could you take him?
您可以安排他來學校嗎？
What do you say, headmaster? Could you enroll him?
校長您覺得怎樣？能招他嗎？
I remember Deva now
我記得Deva
Such a sweet kid. Had excellent grades.
真是個好孩子
He used to play something, too. What was it, a guitar?
他以前彈什麼樂器，是吉他嗎？
- It was a violin. - Yes, it was.
-是小提琴 -是的
Does he still play?
他還在練琴嗎？
No, I'm afraid not.
不了
He doesn't play anymore.
他不再練琴了
Who knows, maybe we'll have him pick it up again.
誰知道了，也許我們會讓他再練起來
Will you enroll him, then?
那您願意招他進來嗎？
To be honest, we don't have a place at the school.
老實說，我們學校真的冇有名額了
But I'll do an exception for your son.
但我會為你兒子破個例
- Thank you. - But...
-謝謝 -但是
The payment will be different this time.
學費金額會有所不同
Since you're here mid-year, you won't get the discount.
由於是期中入學，因此冇有學費摺扣
I trust that's not a problem?
我相信這應該不是問題吧？
- You have a cigarette? - No.
-你有煙嗎？-不
You have money?
有錢嗎？
No.
冇有
How will you screw her, then?
那你要怎麼泡她？
She's a straight up whore.
她是個妓女
And are you her pimp?
你給她拉皮條嗎？
I could be.
我可以拉
Okay.
好吧
And who is your pimp?
誰給你拉皮條？
What did you say? I'll fuck you up.
你說什麼？老子幹死你！
Stop looking at me.
別看著我
Come here.
回來
Stop!
站住！
Come here!
回來！
Agah, don't waste your time.
Agah，別浪費時間了
It's out of order again. I spoke to the mechanic, but he'll come late. He was busy.
電梯又壞了，我給修理工打過電話，但他很忙，會很晚才來
I have the worst luck.
真倒黴
- Rustem. - Yes, sir.
-Rustem -什麼事，先生
- Give me a number. - Are you playing the numbers?
-隨便說個數字 -您在玩數字遊戲嗎？
- Just give me one. - If it wins, we're partners.
-隨便說一個 -如果贏了，我們就是合作夥伴
- 39. - Has to be up to 27.
-39 -不得超過27
If it's above 27, it's not a lucky number, huh?
如果高於27，那不是一個幸運數字，對吧？
Okay then, 24.
那好，24
- No, 26. - Make your mind up.
-不，26 -想好再說
In that case...
這樣的話……
- Who am I speaking to? - I'm from the newspaper Simdi.
-你是誰？-我來自西姆迪報紙
Ates Arbay. How do you do, Nevra?
我是Ates Arbay，你好嗎，Nevra？
Where did you find this number?
您在哪裏找到這個號碼？
I know you're angry, but...
我知道你很生氣，但是……
Why'd you want to have an interview with me?
你為什麼要採訪我？
- They asked me everything. - Yes.
-他們已經問過所有問題了 -是的
I know they did, but...
我知道他們問過，但是
they didn't ask you the right questions.
他們冇有問你正確的問題
What is that gift you have for me that'll be so useful?
那這次採訪對我有什麼好處呢？
Some information that exists in the outer space.
一些存在於外太空的信息
But you can't have it without an interview.
但是不接受採訪就不能給你
I'll be the judge of that.
我來評估一下
I'll have to see what you have.
我要看看你到底有什麼消息
And we'll see what we can do.
看看我們能做什麼
Let's meet. Be at Isyan Sanayi after 10:30, tonight.
今晚10:30我們在Isyan Sanayi見麵
Isyan Sanayi?
- Deva? - It's me, mom.
-Deva？-是我，媽媽
- I... drank a bit. - I know.
-我喝了一點酒 -我知道
Don't tell your father.
不要告訴你父親
Okay, go to sleep.
好，睡吧
Okay. Just, don't tell him.
好嗎，不要告訴他
Don't say that I drank.
不要說我喝酒了
Don't tell him, okay sweetie?
不要告訴他，好嗎親愛的？
What are you doing?
你怎麼開車的？
What is this? Do you want to run me over?
你想撞死我嗎？
Hey.
嘿
- You were going to hit me. - Don't get mad.
-你差點撞到我 -別生氣
I'm out.
我不行了
Goodness.
天意啊
- Do you like the music? - You're wasting your time.
-你喜歡音樂嗎？-你在浪費時間
There's no such thing as 'DJ music'. Never will be.
冇有所謂的“DJ音樂”，永遠不會有
Don't tell anybody.
別跟別人說這句話
Who leaked the news, Ates?
誰泄漏了消息，Ates？
I'll always remember this first time you said my name.
我會永遠記得你第一次叫我的名字
In a moment you asked me something impossible.
你問了一個我不可能回答的問題
Don't do it.
不要這樣
Can I have my gift now?
可以把消息告訴我了嗎？
I don't know. Can you?
我不知道，可以嗎？
First the firewater.
先喝酒吧
- What do you pay for a gram? - What?
-多少錢一克？-什麼？
Cocaine, I mean. How much do you pay?
可卡因，你要付多少錢？
They're overcharging you, I bet.
我敢打賭他們對你要價很高
Don't worry.
不用擔心
You're just an information in an outer space.
你隻是外太空的一個信息
What do you mean?
你什麼意思？
You're just a number in a dealer's mobile phone. See?
您隻是經銷商手機中的一個號碼，懂嗎？
Is there a computer I could use?
這裏有電腦嗎？
You could work here without interruption.
你可以在這工作，不會有人來打擾你
I have to be back on duty.
我要回去工作了
Okay, thanks.
好的，謝謝
Nevra.
- Will I be in trouble? - You will.
-我會有麻煩嗎？-有的
If there's a dealer like that somewhere, you will.
如果這裏有毒販的話，會有的
Glad to meet you, Nevra.
很高興認識你，Nevra
So am I.
我也是
- Are we recording right now? - Yes, we are.
-我們現在在錄音嗎？-是的
- You'll give me a copy, right? - I said okay.
-副本會給我一份，對吧 -可以
I'll read you a list. The courthouse at Cald?ran has burnt down.
我給你看一張清單，Cald?ran法院大樓已經被燒毀
So did the one at Sefilp?nar.
Sefilp?nar法院也是如此
So did the one at Kambura.
還有Kambura法院
But you tell me you had nothing to do with them.
但是你跟我說這些事情都與你無關
No. How could I have the time for all of that?
不，我怎麼有時間做所有這些事情？
Some other brothers must have taken care of them.
一定有別人在做這些事
How did you begin?
你是如何開始的？
There was this man, and he had a file in the courthouse.
有這個人，他在法庭上有一個檔案。
But it's all slander.
但這一切都是誹謗
They made up all the accusations.
他們捏造了所有的指控
And I couldn't stand for any injustice like that.
我不能忍受這樣的不公正
I'm a bailiff there, as you know.
你知道，我是那裏的法警
I burned the whole thing down.
我把所有東西都燒掉了
So that justice prevails in the end, you know?
正義最終會佔上風的，你明白嗎？
Oh, man.
天啊
Oh, man!
天啊！
Why did you shoot me, man?
你為什麼要殺我？
What did I do to you?
我對你做了什麼？
You haven't changed at all, Naimhan.
你根本冇變Naimhan
Not at all.
一點也冇變
You used to be like this.
你以前也是這樣
Always drunk.
總是喝醉
Aren't you afraid of what you'll do to your liver?
你就一點都不擔心你的肝髒嗎？
You wouldn't live long, anyway.
反正你不會長壽
You would live a bit longer, I suppose.
你應該活得更久一點
It wasn't your day.
今天不是你的日子
But so it goes.
但情況就是這樣了
I ran out of petrol.
我冇汽油了
I forgot to fill up the tank.
我忘了加滿油箱
And you suddenly appeared.
然後你突然出現
I wasn't expecting it at all.
我完全冇想到
But the doctor said so.
但是醫生就是這樣說的
Luck really does have to be reckoned with.
運氣確實不容小覷
It's hard to follow people.
跟蹤別人很難
Very hard.
很難
Pursue them all day,
整日追逐他們
wait outside their place.
在他們的房子外麵等
What do they do, where do they go?
他們做什麼，他們去哪裏？
When do they go to sleep, when do they wake up?
他們什麼時候睡覺，什麼時候醒？
It's like having a job.
就像工作
Really.
真的
Man.
老哥
Where do you know me from?
你從哪認識我的？
Where did we meet?
我們在哪見過麵嗎？
Where are you from?
你是哪裏人？
Kambura.
Kambura
And that's where I know you from.
那就是我認識你的地方
Don't do it, man...
別這樣
I beg you, don't, man.
我求求你，別殺我
I'm not doing anything, Naimhan.
我什麼都冇做，Naimhan
I haven't done anything.
我什麼都冇做
You did it.
是你做了
You and them.
你和他們
All of you.
你們所有人
You shouldn't have.
你不該做的
I ONLY TRUST HER. BECAUSE NEVRA UNDERSTANDS ME.
我隻相信她，因為Nevra了解我